

CONTACT

+919995282040

subeeshck3@gmail.com

Chaliyappurath Kuruppath house Moonniyur (POST) Malappuram (DISTRICT) Kerala (STATE), INDIA Pin:676311

EDUCATION

SRI RANGANATHAR INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY [2013-2017] BE MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

(Anna University), Tamilnadu

CERTIFICATIONS

- NDT (ASNT)Level II (SNT-TC-IA)
- QA/QC in mechanical engineering
- QA/QC in welding inspection
- Piping & pipeline engineering

SKILLS

- AUTO CAD design and drafting software.
- Microsoft word, Excel and Power point.
- Isometric, P&ID,
 Equipment's, structural &
 GAD drawings.
- Dimensional checks using Weld gauge, Taper gauge, Hi lo gauge, Fillet gauges ,Vernier caliper.
- Design and analysis software: solid works.
- Effective technical skills.
- Team working skills.
- Confidentiality skills
- Effective communication skills
- Maintain high HSE standards.

LANGUAGES

English : Proficient
Malayalam : Mother tongue
Hindi : Proficient
Tamil : Conversational

SUBEESH CK

QA/QC ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Dedicated QA/QC engineer with more than 3 years experience in Oil&Gas and Power plant Construction and Maintenance projects. Mainly focused on Welding inspection, Welding process and techniques, Various NDT techniques, Piping and pipelines, Tubes, Tanks, Ducts, Steel structure's , Erection, Installation , Torquing and expert in Mechanical drawings.

EXPERIENCE

MECHANICAL ENGINEER (QUALITY DEPARTMENT) BHAVANI ERECTORS PVT LTD with BHEL

September 2020-May 2022

- NTPC-3x660 MW NORTH KARANPURA SUPER THERMAL POWER PLANT PROJECT JHARKHAND (SITE 1)
 - [AIR COOLED CONDENSER- Steam line, Tube bundle, Piping and Structure]
- NTPC-3x800 MW PATRATU SUPER THERMAL POWER PLANT PROJECT JHARKHAND (SITE 2) [BOILER- Critical piping, Structure and Pressure parts]

REFERENCE

Akshay PK (Senior QA/QC Engineer)

Contact : +9186061 64836

Web: WWW.BHAVANIERECTORS.COM

DUTIES&RESPONSIBILITIES

- Daily site surveillance inspection and monitoring of fabrication, Erection, Fit-up, Welding and weld visual inspection activities of pipe lines, tube bundles and other pressure parts.
- Isometric ,P&ID ,Structural and GAD drawings analysis and validation of the work done.
- Co-ordinate with NDT people to complete the NDT activities like penetrant test, preheat, PWHT,PMI and hardness test at site.
- Daily inspection and monitoring of welding and analyses the progress and quality.
- Various NDT report analysis with clients.
- Torquing inspection of structural parts.
- Witnessing welding procedure qualification and welder qualification tests.

NDT TECHNICIAN

IXAR (INDUSTRIAL X-RAY & ALLIED RADIOGRAPHERS (I)PVT LTD.

March 2018-April 2020

- Reliance Industries Ltd Jamnagar ,Gujarat (site 1)
- Reliance Petro Chemical Hazira, Surat, Gujarat (site 2)
- Nayara Energy Ltd Jamnagar, Gujarat (site 3)

SHUTDOWN EXPERIENCES

- Crude-1, CNHT, HYDROGEN (RIL Jamnagar)
- DCU (Nayara energy ltd)

DUTIES&RESPONSIBILITIES

- Maintenance inspection in various plants by the instruction of engineers using various NDT methods
- Penetrant test inspection in new weld joints in pipe lines and many other equipment's.
- Thickness measurement using ultrasonic thickness gauge in pipelines ,tubes ,storage tanks ,columns and other equipment's.
- Ultrasonic testing in weld joints and other areas with corrosion and various defects.
- PMI and Hardness inspection in pipes ,nuts ,bolts and other equipment's & parts.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above information are true and correct to best of my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned particulars.

Sincerely Place :Malappuram
Subeesh ck Date :04-04-2023